Paulo César Vieira Ruzanovsky

pauloruzanovsky@gmail.com ❖ +5547999487723 ❖ linkedin ❖ portfolio

Production Engineer with five years of experience in demand planning, proficiency in data extraction, processing, and analysis with SQL, Excel and Python. Expertise extends to BI tools, including Power BI, Tableau and Qlik Sense, and practical experience with SAP ERP.

TECH KNOWLEDGE

Excel | Google Sheets | Python | SQL | BI | Qlik Sense | PowerBI | Tableau | ETL | SAP | Data Analysis | Optimization

EXPERIENCES

Nidec GA Mar.2023 – Current

SnOE Senior Analyst

- I led a team of three analysts, focusing on optimizing production planning across the supply chain. I collected and analyzed data from SAP and processed information in Excel and Google Sheets.
- Participated heavily in the process of bringing data from SAP to BigQuery, being the bridge with the IT team defining the business rules. This enabled us to gather and transform data faster and more reliably, improving the data analysis process.
- In response to persistent challenges in logistics, particularly discrepancies between actual customer needs and ERP data affecting the materials team, I took the lead on a project in collaboration with the IT team. Our focus was on rectifying the business rule within the ERP, resulting in a significant enhancement of accuracy. This initiative not only successfully addressed the identified pain point but also yielded benefits, including notable reductions in inventory levels and airfreight costs.
- I developed strategic dashboards using Qlik Sense and Power BI, providing in-depth analysis of demand and production capacity. I presented these dashboards in a weekly meeting with over 30 colleagues, including managers and directors, influencing crucial production decisions.

Nidec GA Feb.2021 – Mar.2023

SnOE Mid-level Analyst

Joinville - SC, Brazil

Joinville - SC, Brazil

- Leveling of production plans to ensure on-time deliveries and mitigate risks related to raw materials and manufacturing capacity.
- Development of performance indicators related to demand and production capacity using Qlik Sense.
- I streamlined frequently repeated demand analysis processes using Excel/Google Sheets, eliminating operational workload for the team.

Nidec GA Mar.2018 – Jan.2020

SnOE Intern

Joinville - SC, Brazil

- Providing support to the Sales and Operations Execution (S&OE) team in operational demand analysis tasks.
- Crafting automation tools for the demand planning process, leveraging my Excel expertise, leading to a substantial reduction in processing time.
- Designing and overseeing performance indicators utilizing tools such as Power BI and Google Datastudio.

EDUCATION

Universidade do Estado de Santa Catarina - CCT

Aug.2013 - Aug.2021

Bachelor in Production Engineering

Joinville, SC

Unisociesc

MBA in Business Intelligence, Management e Analytics

Set.2023 - Set.2024

Joinville, SC

EDUCATION

Udemy Out.2023 - Nov.2023 Microsoft Power BI Desktop for Business Intelligence (2023) Joinville, SC Out.2023 - Out.2023 Udemy Tableau 2022 A-Z: Hands-On Tableau Training for Data Science Joinville, SC

Udemy Set.2023 - Out.2023 SQL - MySQL for Data Analytics and Business Intelligence Joinville, SC